Tassilo Bouwman

UX Designer & Mobile Developer

portfolio bouwman.me

CONTACT +49 151 64302730 tassilo@bouwman.me

With my unique background in UX, software development and marketing I design usable interfaces with technical possibilities and business needs in mind and collaborate with stakeholders effectively. As a MSc student in Human-Computer Interaction at UCL I developed skills in user research and interaction design and applied them in projects such as the CHI Student Design Competition (2nd out of 79), premier conference of Human-Computer Interaction. As an iOS Developer I implemented large-scale mobile apps and collaborated in an agile team.

Education

GRADUATION SEP 2018

MSc Human Computer Interaction

University College London (UCL), United Kingdom

- Relevant courses: Interaction Design & Science, Affective Interaction, Future Interfaces, Physical Prototyping
- Thesis: "Using a mobile app to conduct a visual search experiment"

GRADUATION SEP 2015

BSc Information Systems

Europäische Fachhochschule Brühl (1st), Germany

- Relevant courses: Project & Team Management, Business Application Systems, Web Development, Marketing
- Thesis: "Development of a mobile application to support approval tasks"

JAN 2015 - JUN 2015

Semester Abroad

University of California Santa Barbara, US

 Relevant courses: International Communication, Marketing in the 21st century, Google Analytics

Skills

Tools

Sketch, Framer, Adobe Illustrator, Adobe Photoshop, Adobe XD, InVision, Balsamiq, Axure, Autodesk Fusion 360, Omnigraffle, Keynote, SPSS, Git, Android Studio, Xcode

Code

Swift, Java, C#, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Objective-C, SQL, R

Design

Affinity Diagrams, Personas, Wireframes, Flows, Mock-ups, Usability Testing, A/B Testing, Web Analytics, and more!

Languages

German, English (C2), French (A2), Spanish (A2)

Experience

2015 - 2016

iOS Developer Internship (6 month)

adesso mobile solutions GmbH, Germany

- Developed large-scale mobile apps in an agile process
- Implemented design specifications from mockups
- Collaborated in a team using Git, Confluence & Gira
- Tested, reviewed & documented code

2012 - 2015

IT-Systems Sales Trainee (3 years)

Bull GmbH, Germany

- Communicated with clients to gather requirements
- Developed an Android app using Android Studio
- Defined IT-service processes using flow diagrams

Awards & Activities

SEP 2017 - APR 2018

CHI Student Design Competition

Finished 2nd out of 79 teams

- Designed a feedback system for an urban farm
- User research employing interviews & personas
- Communicated design ideas via sketches & scenarios
- Wrote a paper about the user-centred design approach

MAY 2017 - MAY 2018

Marketing Officer

UCL Hiking Club

- Designed website, social media presence & t-shirts
- Iteratively refined designs using Sketch & Illustrator
- Define information architecture of the website

JAN 2017 - APR 2017

Student Game Design Competition

CHI Play 2017

- Designed a game to raise awareness of air pollution
- Prototyped game using paper & software prototypes
- Evaluated experience using think aloud & interviews